lan Matsumoto

DATA SPECIALIST

CONTACT



https://github.com/ianmat55



808-679-7230



ianmat55@gmail.com

PROFILE

Ian Matsumoto is an analyst and aspiring software engineer. Traveling to the Bay Area from his hometown of Honolulu HI, Ian is pursuing his passion for creative innovation through a career in technology. He carries with him 5+ years of experience with GIS technologies, a love for computer science, and an exceptional work ethic.

EDUCATION

University of Redlands

Bachelor of Science (2015-2019)

Environmental Science

GIS

Mathematics

SKILLS

Technologies:

Git

GIS based systems

Languages:

Python

SQL

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Node

Professional:

PROJECTS

Hire.me

technologies | Node, Express, Postgresql, HTML/CSS/EJS

Website that scrapes linkedin, indeed and glassdoor for jobs that meet specified criteria, store marked postings and send a weekly email of relevant results. Hire was built to streamline my job searching process and also serve as a portfolio piece.

- Built a REST API using Node and Express that scrapes multiple websites for jobs and returns it to the client in a nicely formatted table.
- Webscraper runs on form submit via asynchronous request
- Used Postgres database to store user information
- Requested data server-side and rendered tables dynamically with EJS
- User account creation and login system with functionality for storing and tracking interesting job listings

CLI Websocket Chatbot

technologies | Python, Socket Communication

In terminal chatroom utilizing socket and top communication. The multi-client server class inherits from the base client class, accepting other client connections and relaying data to all users in the room.

- Used Python's socket library to create a multi-client server and client in terminal
- Scripted CLI commands that perform specific actions such as kicking clients from the server, sending files, and direct messaging

QA processing	
New hire training	
Technical writing	
Adaptability	
Time management	
Worflow documentation	

- Utilized threading to allow client and server to both recieve and send messages on user input
- Used python's rich library for command line UI

Birthday Storage App

technologies | Flask, mySQL, HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Flask CRUD application that stores friend's birthday and and name.

- Simple **CRUD** application using SQLite as a database for its lightweight and speedy implementation
- Front end interface coded with basic html/css/javascript and bootstrap library

JOB HISTORY

Data Annotation Specialist

Tesla | 10/2020 - present

Assist in the training and development of Tesla autopilot ai through the use of GIS and data labeling

- · Served as a bottleneck of data labeling for six teams, identifying areas critical to training the neural network
- labled and verified an average of 100 data sets per day in a dynamic workflow
- Serve as a critical asset to the QA team and learned about the general workflow to QA process. Identify and resolve Quality Assurance workflow issues and improvement initiatives.
- · Drive teams to improve processes, explicate data and yield meaningful metrics.
- Direct two daily feedback reports for engineering, project management, and leadership teams.
- · Worked in dynamic environment helping with various teams and filling numerous roles under Tesla autopilot

Freelance Web Developer

2/2021 - present

Self-taught programmer specializing in website development using Wordpress and Shopify.

- Create websites for a running total of three clients on Wordpress and Shopify
- Work with hosting platforms, content management systems and APIs
- · Specialize in commerce development as well as personal/professional website development

GIS Analyst

Apple via Apex Systems (Contract) | 07/2019 - 09/2020

Used GIS software to mark construction projects that would affect routing or address changes in Apple Maps

- · Conduct web research on construction projects and track their progress through Apple's GIS software
- Responsible for updated and tracking maps in Riverside, San Bernardino, and Orange County
- Monitor traffic and pedestrian density on maps to identify areas of potential construction
- · Communicate and collaborate with city/county officials, private companies and peers regarding new projects